Indiana University President's Office records, 1937-1962 C213
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University President's Office records
1937-1962
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University. President
C213
612 cubic feet 617 boxes
The first president of what was then Indiana College was elected by the Board of Trustees in 1829. Herman B Wells was named interim president in 1937 and president in 1938, a position he held until 1962. Collection consists primarily of correspondence, reports, and publications. A particularly rich collection, correspondence is to and from Wells and other high ranking university administrators. The files are arranged alphabetically.
Access Restrictions
Select files are closed to researchers. These are indicated in the finding aid.
Advance notice is required for access.
Administrative History
Herman B Wells was born on June 7, 1902, in Jamestown, Indiana to Joseph and Anna Wells. In 1920, he graduated from Lebanon High School. Wells initially enrolled at the University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign but transferred to Indiana University in 1921 at the beginning of his sophomore year. While a student at IU, he was a member of the Sigma Nu fraternity, treasurer of the Union Board, member of the YMCA Cabinet, and business manager of the YMCA Red Book. Wells graduated from IU in 1924 with a Bachelor of Science in Commerce. After graduation, Wells worked as an assistant bank cashier at the First National Bank of Lebanon, Indiana for two years before continuing his education at IU. He graduated in 1927 with a Master of Arts in Economics. Wells began studying for his Ph.D. in Economics at University of Wisconsin-Madison but left school to take a job with the Indiana Bankers Association.
In 1930, Wells became an instructor in IU's Department of Economics and Sociology in addition to working for the IBA. He became Assistant Professor in Economics in 1933 but took a two year leave of absence from IU to work for the Indiana Department for Financial Institutions. In 1935, Wells returned to IU and was appointed dean of the business school. After the retirement of IU President William Lowe Bryan, Wells became interim president in 1937 and was elected the 11th President of Indiana University in 1938. Under the leadership of President Wells, IU transformed from a small, locally oriented college to a world-class institution of higher learning through expanded enrollment, recruitment of new faculty, construction of new buildings, new program efforts, and campus beautification projects. He was a steadfast supporter of IU's faculty and students especially in the areas of academic freedom and civil rights. In 1962, Wells retired as IU's president and was named Chancellor of Indiana University, the first to hold that position. His primary duties as chancellor included special projects, fundraising, conferring with private donors, administrative duties, attending cultural and athletic events, and acting as senior advisor to the university. After the resignation of IU President Elvis Stahr, Wells served as IU's interim president from July to November 1968. While chancellor, Wells wrote his autobiography Being Lucky: Reminiscences and Reflections which was published in 1980. He maintained an office at IU until his death on March 18, 2000, at the age of 97.
In addition to his roles at Indiana University, Wells held many appointed positions over the course of his career. He served as an economic analyst for the U.S. State Department's Office of Foreign Economic Cooperation from 1943-1944, as cultural affairs adviser to the U.S. Military Government in West Germany from 1947 to 1948, and as adviser to the Ministry of Pakistan in 1959 among other appointments. Wells was a member and served in leadership roles for several education foundations. He was a member of presidential committees on overseas voluntary activities and U.S.-Soviet trade relations.
Wells was the recipient of numerous honors and awards including twenty-eight honorary degrees. Since 1962, Indiana University has given the Herman B Wells Senior Recognition Award annually to an IU senior who exhibits a strong academic record, as well as leadership and service to the university. The IU Foundation established the Herman B Wells Scholar Program which provides four-year academic scholarships to a selective group of IU Bloomington students. The main library at IU Bloomington was named the Herman B Wells Library in his honor in 2005.
Please see Jim Capshew's brief biography of Herman Wells at http://www.indiana.edu/~libarch/Wells/wellsbio.html.
Arrangement
Organized in a single series, Subject files; Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Scope and Content Note
Following the original order of the records, files are arranged alphabetically by folder heading. Collection is a rich source of university history during this time period, consisting not only of Wells's correspondence, but also the correspondence of several high ranking administrators.
Additions may be made to the collection as additional records are interfiled. Please contact Archives staff for further information.
Separated Material
Any photographs found in the collection have been transferred to the Archives Photographs Collection.
Acquisition Information
Accession number 1117.
Appraisal
Duplicates and some routine correspondence removed.
College presidents --Indiana --Archives.; College presidents --Indiana --Correspondence.; Universities and colleges --Indiana --Administration.; Wells, Herman B -- Correspondence; Wells, Herman B -- Archives; Indiana University -- Administration; Indiana University. President -- Archives; Indiana University. President -- Records and correspondence; Indiana University. President -- History -- 20th century -- Sources
- Subject files, 1937-1962
  - List of Special Folders in General File, 1952-1953 (Box 1)
  - List of Folders in Executive Action File, 1953-1955; (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Registrar's Material Discarded from the Files, 1952-1953 (Box 1)
  - Registrar's Material Discarded from the Files, 1953-1954 (Box 1)
  - A, 1937-1956; (19 folders) (Box 1)
  - A, 1956-1962; (6 folders) (Box 2)
  - Ab, 1947-1955; (8 folders) (Box 2)
  - Abr, 1937-1962; (25 folders) (Box 2)
  - Ac, 1937-1955; (12 folders) (Box 2)
  - Academic Costume - The History of in America, 1939-40 (Box 2)
  - Academic Freedom of Faculty, 1939-40 (Box 2)
  - Academic Salaries (Box 2)
  - Acceleration of College Programs, 1950-51 (Box 2)
  - Acceleration Problems, 1942-43 (Box 2)
  - Accounting Conference, 1938-39 (Box 2)
  - Accounting Department, 1949-1962; (10 folders) (Box 2)
  - Accounting Department Memos, 1948-1955; (6 folders) (Box 2)
  - Accounting Department Procedure, 1950s (Box 2)
  - Accounting Office - memos to staff re: budgets, etc., 1947-48 (Box 2)
  - Accreditation of Service Experiences, 1959-60 (Box 2)
  - Accrediting Agencies, 1940-1952; (12 folders) (Box 2)
  - Accrediting Agencies, 1952-1962; (10 folders) (Box 3)
  - Accrediting - School of Nursing, 1938 (Box 3)
  - Acoustical Materials Association, 1937-38 (Box 3)
  - Activities Fees, 1939-40 (Box 3)
  - Ad, 1937-1962; (25 folders) (Box 3)
  - Adams, 1947-48 (Box 3)
  - Adams, 1948-1955; (6 folders) (Box 4)
  - Adams, James S., 1960 (Box 4)
  - Adams, Mildred, 1946-1961 (Box 4)
  - Ade, 1937-41; (4 folders) (Box 4)
  - Administration Building Space (Box 4)
  - Admin./President's Office: Visitors to Campus, 1950-1951; (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Administrative, 1961-1962; (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Administrative Applications -V.P. -promotional work, etc., 1940-1941 (Box 4)
  - Administrative Classification (Box 4)
  - Administrative Committee Action, 1960-1961 (Box 4)
  - Administrative Committee, 1947-1958; (10 folders) (Box 4)
  - Administrative Committee Bloomington campus, 1959-1960 (Box 4)
  - Administrative Committee, 1960s (Box 4)
  - Administrative Committee Miscellaneous, 1959-1961; (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Administrative Committee (Dean of the Faculties Matters), 1960-1961 (Box 4)
  - Administrative Committee Dean of the Faculties Office, 1961-1962 (Box 4)
  - Administrative Committee (other matters), 1961-1962 (Box 4)
  - Administrative Committee Meetings - Medical Center, 1959-1960 (Box 4)
  - Administrative Committee - Complete Set of Minutes, 1947-1948 (Box 4)
  - Administrative Committee - Minutes: Duplicates, 1947-1948 (Box 4)
  - Administrative Committee – Minutes, 1950-1951 (Box 4)
  - Administrative Committee-Minutes, 1951-1957; (9 folders) (Box 5)
  - Administrative Committee (Pending Business), 1959-1960 (Box 5)
  - Administrative Committee Minutes, 1960-1962; (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Administrative Council, 1939-1958; (11 folders) (Box 5)
  - Administrative Council Minutes, 1942-1951; (11 folders) (Box 5)
  - Administrative and Maintenance Equipment Committee, 1945-1946 (Box 5)
  - Administrative Manual Procedures, 1958-1959 (Box 5)
  - Administrative Office – Applications, 1937-1938 (Box 5)
  - Committee on Administrative Research, 1940-1943; (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Administrative Research, 1941-1943; (5 folders) (Box 5)
  - Administrative Salary List, 1960s (Box 5)
  - Administrative Staff - New (Box 5)
  - Administrative Studies, 1949-1950s (Box 5)
  - Administrative Studies - Janitorial Costs, 1953-1954 (Box 5)
  - Division of Administrative Studies Manual, Study of Instructional Costs, 1954-1955 (Box 5)
  - Administrative War Council, 1942-1946; (4 folders) (Box 5)
  - Admissions (Box 5)
  - Office of Admissions Five-Year Report, 1937-1942 (Box 5)
  - Admissions - Statistics, IU, 1939-1940 (Box 6)
  - Admissions Office Applications, 1940 (Box 6)
  - Admissions, 1942-1960; (8 folders) (Box 6)
  - Admissions - Entrance requirements at state universitites (Purdue), 1955 (Box 6)
  - Admissions, 1960-1962; (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Office of Admissions Annual Report, 1938-1946; (6 folders) (Box 6)
  - Director of Admissions Two-Year Report, 1942-1944 (Box 6)
  - Office of Records and Admissions Annual Report, 1949-1961; (10 folders) (Box 6)
  - Records and Admissions, 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Office of Records and Admissions Annual Report, 1961-1962 (Box 6)
  - Admissions Committee Minutes, 1958-1959 (Box 6)
  - Admissions Conference Purdue Univ., 1947 (Box 6)
  - Office of Admissions Annual Report, 1937-1938 (Box 6)
  - Director of Admissions, 1938-1941 (Box 6)
  - Admissions - Enrollment Estimate (Box 6)
  - Admissions Meeting, 1950 (Box 6)
  - Admission Requirements, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Admissions Requirements Committee, 1956-1961 (Box 6)
  - Admissions Reports, 1945-1955; (10 folders) (Box 6)
  - Admissions - Out of State Students, 1955-1960; (3 folders) (Box 6)
  - Admission of Students to Indiana State, Ball State, and Canterbury, 1946-1947 (Box 6)
  - Adult Education Bill, 1943-1944 (Box 6)
  - Adult Education, 1945-1946 (Box 6)
  - Adult Education, 1946-1947 (Box 6)
  - Adult Education and Public Service - All Branches Fund #2008, 1946-1947 (Box 6)
  - Adult Education and Public Service, 1946-1947; (8 folders) (Box 6)
  - Adult Education, 1947-1948 (Box 6)
  - Adult Education Division - Bureau of Community Organization, 1947-1948 (Box 6)
  - Adult Education and Public Service - All Branches Fund #2008, 1947-1948 (Box 6)
  - Adult Education and Public Service, 1947-1948; (8 folders) (Box 6)
  - Adult Education Workshop, 1947-1948 (Box 6)
  - Division of Adult Education and Public Services Annual Report, 1947-1948 (Box 6)
  - Fund 2008: Adult Education and Public Service, 1948 (Box 6)
  - Adult Education, 1948-1949 (Box 6)
  - Adult Education Division - Bureau of Community Organization, 1948-1949 (Box 6)
  - Adult Education and Public Service - All Branches Fund #2008, 1948-1949 (Box 6)
  - Adult Education and Public Service, 1948-1949; (5 folders) (Box 6)
  - Adult Education and Public Service, 1948-1949; (4 folders) (Box 7)
  - Division of Adult Education and Public Services Annual Report, 1948-1949 (Box 7)
  - Fund 2008: Adult Education and Public Service, 1949 (Box 7)
  - Adult Education, 1949-1950 (Box 7)
  - Adult Education and Public Services - Bureau of Community Organization, 1949-1950; (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Adult Education and Public Service - All Branches Fund #2008, 1949-1950 (Box 7)
  - Adult Education and Public Service, 1949-1950; (8 folders) (Box 7)
  - Division of Adult Education and Public Services Annual Report, 1949-1950 (Box 7)
  - Adult Education and Public Service, Fund 2008, 1950 (Box 7)
  - Adult Education – Miscellaneous, 1950-1951 (Box 7)
  - Adult Education Division, 1950-1951; (3 folders) (Box 7)
  - Adult Education and Public Services - Bureau of Community Organization, 1950-1951 (Box 7)
  - Adult Education and Public Service - All Branches Fund #2008, 1950-1951 (Box 7)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, 1950-1951; (9 folders) (Box 7)
  - Division of Adult Education and Public Services Annual Report, 1950-1951 (Box 7)
  - Adult Education – Miscellaneous, 1951-1952 (Box 7)
  - Adult Education Division, 1951-1952; (3 folders) (Box 7)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, 1951-1952; (6 folders) (Box 7)
  - Adult Education - Fort Wayne Extension Center, 1951-1952 (Box 7)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, 1951-1952; (4 folders) (Box 7)
  - Division of Adult Education and Public Services Annual Report, 1951-1952 (Box 7)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, 1951-1953; (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Adult Education Dean, 1951 (Box 8)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, 1952-1953 (Box 8)
  - Adult Education Division - Comparative Bookstore Balance Sheet, 1952-1953 (Box 8)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, 1952-1953; (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Adult Education – Miscellaneous, 1952-1953 (Box 8)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, 1952-1953; (5 folders) (Box 8)
  - Adult Education - Jeffersonville - Extension Center, 1954-1955 (Box 8)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, 1952-1953; (3 folders) (Box 8)
  - Adult Education – Miscellaneous, 1953-1954 (Box 8)
  - Adult Education Division - All Centers. Analysis of income., 1953-1954 (Box 8)
  - Division of Adult Education and Public Services Annual Report, 1953-1954 (Box 8)
  - Adult Education Division, 1953-1954; (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, 1953-1954; (13 folders) (Box 8)
  - Adult Education (Dean Briscoe's Files), 1954 (Box 8)
  - Division of Adult Education and Public Services Annual Report, 1954-1955 (Box 8)
  - Adult Education – Miscellaneous, 1954-1955 (Box 8)
  - Adult Education - Gary Center Site. Official Correspondence., 1954-1955 (Box 8)
  - Adult Education- Gary Center Site. Letters from Individuals and Groups, 1954-1955 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services - All Centers, 1954-1955 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services - Annual Report, 1954-1955 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education Division - Comparative General Finance Report, 1954-1955 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Bloomington, 1954-1955 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Calumet, 1954-1955 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Fort Wayne, 1954-1955 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Indianapolis, 1954-1955 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Kokomo, 1954-1955 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Southbend, 1954-1955 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Southeastern, 1954-1955 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Audio Visual Center, 1954-1955 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Enrollments, 1954-1955 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Dean Briscoe's file, 1954-1955; (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, All Centers, 1955-1956; (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Division of Adult Education and Public Services, Annual Report, 1955-1956 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Bureau of Community Organization, 1955-1956 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Comparative Bookstore Balance Sheets, 1955-1956 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Comparative General Financial Sheet, 1955-1956 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Conference on Liberal Education of Adults, 1955-1956 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Audio Visual Center, 1955-1956 (Box 9)
    General
    Includes: Subversive Influence in the Educational Process. Part 8 hearings before the United States Senate Committee on the Judiciary, first session, on Apr. 23-25, May 5, 1953
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Bloomington, 1955-1956 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Calumet, 1955-1956 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Fort Wayne, 1955-1956 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Gary, 1955-1956 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Indianapolis, 1955-1956 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Kokomo, 1955-1956 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Miscellaneous, 1955-1956 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, South Bend, 1955-1956; (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Southeastern, 1955-1956 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education, 1956-1957; (3 folders) (Box 9)
  - Adult Education – Enrollments, 1956-1957 (Box 9)
  - Adult Education Division, All Centers, 1956-1957 (Box 10)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Comparative Bookstore Balance Sheets, 1956-1957; (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Comparative General Financial Report, 1956-1957 (Box 10)
  - Adult Education Division - Audio Visual Center (Box 10)
    - General, 1956-1957 (Box 10)
    - Net Film Service, 1956-1957 (Box 10)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Bloomington, 1956-1957 (Box 10)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Bureau of Community Organization, 1956-1957 (Box 10)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Calumet, 1956-1957 (Box 10)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Fort Wayne, 1956-1957 (Box 10)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Gary, 1956-1957 (Box 10)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Indianapolis, 1956-1957 (Box 10)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Kokomo, 1956-1957 (Box 10)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, South Bend, 1956-1957 (Box 10)
  - Adult Education and Public Services, Southeastern, 1956-1957 (Box 10)
  - Adult Education Supplementary Budget, 1956-1957 (Box 10)
  - Adult Education Miscellaneous, 1957-1960; (3 files) (Box 10)
  - Bureau of Studies in Adult Education Annual Report, 1960-1961 (Box 10)
  - Adult Education, 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Advertising Council, 1956 (Box 10)
  - Advisory Committee on Cultural Exchange with Occupied Countries, 1948 (Box 10)
  - Advisory Committee on Penal Classification, 1937-1938 (Box 10)
  - Advisory Committee - Wells Successor, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Advisory Council Committee, 1937-1938 (Box 10)
  - Advisory Seminar on Implementation of Recommendations of Pakistan Commission on National Education, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Aeons, Board of (Box 10)
    - 1937-1938 (Box 10)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 10)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 10)
    - 1940-1941 (Box 10)
    - 1941-1942 (Box 10)
    - 1942-1943 (Box 10)
    - 1943-1944 (Box 10)
    - 1944-1945 (Box 10)
    - 1945-1946 (Box 10)
    - 1946-1947 (Box 10)
    - 1947-1948 (Box 10)
    - 1948-1949 (Box 10)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 10)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 10)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 10)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 10)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 10)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 10)
    - 1959-1962 (Box 10)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 10)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Aeroplane - Time tables, etc., 1937-1938 (Box 10)
  - Aetna, 1961 (Box 10)
  - Africa, 1958-1959 (Box 10)
  - African-American Institute (New York, NY), 1960 (Box 10)
  - African American Students Foundation, Inc., 1960 (Box 10)
  - African Scholarship Program of American Universities, 1961 (Box 10)
  - African Students, 1960-1961 (Box 10)
  - African Studies Program Annual Report, 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - Ag, 1937-1962; (25 files) (Box 10)
  - Airborne Television, 1959-1960 (Box 10)
  - Air Corps, 1941-1942 (Box 10)
  - Air Force Language Training Program, 1952-1962 (Box 10)
  - Air Force ROTC, 1956-1957 (Box 10)
  - Air Mail Schedule, 1940-1941 (Box 10)
  - Airport, before, 1941-1945; (5 files) (Box 10)
  - Airport, University, 1945 (Box 10)
  - Alan, Hubert – Passport, 1940-1941 (Box 10)
  - Al, 1937-1942; (5 files) (Box 10)
  - Al, 1942-1962; (20 folders) (Box 10)
  - Alabama, University of, 1937-1959; (12 folders) (Box 11)
  - Trip to Tuscaloosa, Ala. for Inauguration of President, Univ. of Alabama, 1957-1958 (Box 11)
  - Alcoholism - School of Alcohol Studies Proposed (Box 11)
  - Alcoholism (Box 11)
  - Ale, 1937-1962; (25 folders) (Box 11)
  - Alexander, W.A., 1937-1940; (4 folders) (Box 11)
  - Alexander, W. A., 1938-1944; (14 folders) (Box 12)
  - All, 1937-1962; (25 folders) (Box 12)
  - Allen, 1949-1955; (6 folders) (Box 12)
  - Allen, Dotaline, 1944-1961 (Box 12)
  - Allen, Frank E., 1940-1953; (13 folders) (Box 12)
  - Allen, Frank, 1955 (Box 12)
  - Allen, Robert, 1937-1942; (5 folders) (Box 12)
  - Alli, 1938-1962; (23 folders) (Box 13)
  - Allied Health Services, 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Allied Mission for Observing Greek Elections, 1946-1947 (Box 13)
  - Allman, H.B. Summer Session Head, 1945-1947; (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Alpha Delta Pi, 1940-1942 (Box 13)
  - Alpha Hall, 1937-1961 (Box 13)
  - Alpha Phi Omega, 1938-1941 (Box 13)
  - Alpha Tau Emega, 1938-1942 (Box 13)
  - Alumni Association Audit by D.L. Dreterle, 1939-1940 (Box 13)
  - Alumni Association, 1941-1942 (Box 13)
  - Alumni Association – Bryan Portrait, 1959 (Box 13)
  - Alumni Association Executive Council, 1941-1950 (Box 13)
  - Alumni Association Centennial Moving Picture, 1954 (Box 13)
  - Alumni Association, 1961-1962 (Box 13)
  - Alumni Association - DASA (Box 13)
  - Alumni Office Annual Report, 1937-1938 (Box 13)
  - Alumni Secretary Five-Year Report, 1937-1938 (Box 13)
  - Alumni Office Annual Report, 1938-1940; (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Alumni Secretary Annual Report, 1942-1943 (Box 13)
  - Alumni Secretary Two-Year Report, 1942-1944 (Box 13)
  - Alumni Secretary Annual Report, 1944-1946; (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Alumni Office - Annual Report, 1947-1959; (5 folders) (Box 13)
  - Indiana University Alumni Association Annual Report, 1959-1962; (3 folders) (Box 13)
  - Alumni Clubs (Box 13)
  - Alumni Clubs Presidents Luncheon, 1952 (Box 13)
  - Alumni Council and Alumni Misc., 1937-1940; (3 folders) (Box 13)
  - Alumni Association, 1940-1941 (Box 13)
  - Alumni Council and Alumni Misc., 1940-1952; (12 folders) (Box 13)
  - Alumni Council and Alumni Misc., 1952-1962; (10 folders) (Box 13)
  - Alumni Day, 1947-1948 (Box 14)
  - Alumni RE: Developing, 1939-1940 (Box 14)
  - Alumni Directory - Regarding Publication of a new one, 1938-1939 (Box 14)
  - Alumni - Distinguished Alumni Service Award Recipients, 1953-1962; (6 folders) (Box 14)
  - Alumni District Councillors, 1937-1941; (5 folders) (Box 14)
  - Alumni - Football (Box 14)
  - Alumni of Indianapolis and Marion County Legislators Meeting, 1949 (Box 14)
  - Alumni Institute (Box 14)
  - Alumni Letters of Appreciation, 1939-1940 (Box 14)
  - Admin. Letter, 1943-1944 (Box 14)
  - Alumni Letters (Printed), 1944-1945 (Box 14)
  - I.U. Alumni Magazine Financial Analyses by Managing Editor, 1938-1939 (Box 14)
  - Indiana Alumni Magazine, 1937-1960; (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - Alumni Meetings, 1939-1940 (Box 14)
  - Alumni Office, 1958-1959 (Box 14)
  - Alumni Service Award, 1952-1957; (5 folders) (Box 14)
  - Alumni Visiting Committee – Miscellaneous, 1949-1951; (7 folders) (Box 14)
  - Am, 1937-1939; (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - Am, 1939-1962; (23 folders) (Box 15)
  - American – Miscellaneous, 1940-1951; (7 folders) (Box 15)
  - American Miscellaneous, 1951-1962; (12 folders) (Box 16)
  - American Academy of Political and Social Sciences (Box 16)
  - American Alumni Council Conference, French Lick Springs, Indiana, 1939-1940 (Box 16)
  - American Alumni Council News, 1937-1938 (Box 16)